CIFAR-10 is a popular dataset of 60,000 tiny images,
CIFAR-10 是一个热门的数据集 其中包含 60,000 个小图片
each depicting an object from one of 10 classes.
每个都描绘了一种对象 共有 10 个类别
We'll be using this dataset to perform image classification.
我们将使用该数据集进行图片分类
You're encouraged to follow along in the Jupyter notebook linked below.
建议你按照下面链接的 Jupyter notebook 跟着操作
It's relatively easy to import this dataset in keras.
将此数据集导入 keras 相对比较简单
We need to import one python module and then it's only one line of
我们需要导入一个 python 模块
code to get our train and test images along with their corresponding labels.
然后 只需一行代码 就能开始训练并用相应的标签测试图片
Let's visualize a small subset of these training images.
我们可视化这些训练图片的一个小子集
As expected, there are ships,
和预期的一样 数据集中有船只
dogs and horses along with other object categories we expect to see in the dataset.
狗狗 马以及其他对象类别
As before we add the additional preprocessing step of
和之前一样 我们添加一个预处理步骤
dividing every pixel in every image by 255.
将每个图片中的每个像素除以 255
So now each image array has entries between 0 and 1.
现在每个图片数组的条目是在 0 到 1 之间
We also break off a validation set so that we're left with
我们还拿出了验证集
45,000 training images and 5,000 validation images.
所以现在是 45,000 张训练图片和 5,000 张验证图片
We set aside 10,000 images for testing the accuracy of our network after training.
再留出 10,000 张图片 在训练之后测试网络的准确性
Each image is truly tiny,
每个图片都很小
only 32 pixels high and 32 pixels wide.
只有 32 像素高和 32 像素宽
Each has a color image so interpreted by that computer as an array with a depth of three.
每个都是彩色图片 计算机将它们解读为深度为 3 的数组
The first model we'll train is a regular vanilla neural network.
我们将训练的第一个模型是普通的 Vanilla 神经网络
Recall that we'll have to first flatten each image to
我们首先需要将每个图片扁平化为向量
a vector and all of the spatial information will be lost.
所有空间信息将丢失
Then we'll feed it to an MLP with two hidden layers.
然后将该向量提供给具有两个隐藏层的 MLP
Notice the number of parameters,
注意参数的数量
it's over three and a half million.
超过 305 万个
Do you think this approach will work well?
你觉得该方法可行吗？
Random guessing would correspond to an accuracy of roughly one in 10 or 10%.
随机猜测的准确率大概在 10% 左右
Do you think the MLP will beat this?
你认为 MLP 的准确率会超过这一值吗？
If so, by how much?
如果能超过 超过多少？
We'll use the same loss function and optimizer as before,
我们将使用和之前一样的损失函数和优化程序
then we train the model for 20 epochs where we
然后对模型训练 20 个 epoch
save the weights that get the best validation accuracy.
并保存验证准确率最高的权重
If you run the notebook yourself,
如果你自己运行 notebook
feel free to increase the number of epochs or modify other hyper parameters.
可以增加 epoch 数量或修改其他超参数
Once the training has finished,
训练完毕后
we can load the saved model weights.
我们可以加载保存的模型权重
And we attain roughly 40% accuracy on the test set.
测试集的准确率大概是 40%
It's better than random guessing but hopefully a CNN will do much better.
比随机猜测的效果好 但是希望 CNN 的效果好很多
So let's open the other notebook.
我们打开另一个 notebook
All of the importing and pre-processing steps are the same.
所有导入和预处理步骤都一样
We define the CNN architecture in Step Five of the notebook.
我们在 notebook 的第五步定义 CNN 架构
The CNN should look very familiar from the previous video.
根据之前的视频 CNN 应该看起来很熟悉
The image is first fed through a sequence of
图片首先经过一系列的卷积层和最大池化层
convolutional and max pooling layers designed to squeeze out the spatial information.
旨在挤压出空间信息
Then we flatten the image and add a couple of fully connected layers.
然后扁平化图片 并添加几个完全连接层
The only thing that should look different is the dropout layers,
唯一的区别是 dropout 层
we have added those to minimize overfitting.
我们添加了这些 dropout 层 以便尽量避免过拟合
Notice that this network uses far fewer parameters than the MLP we just trained,
注意 这个网络用到的参数比我们刚刚训练的 MLP 少了很多
but hopefully it will do a much better job on the classification task.
但是希望它能更好地完成分类任务
Let's continue to use the same loss function and optimizer.
继续使用相同的损失函数和优化程序
We train the model for 100 epochs with the batch size of 32.
对模型训练 100 个 epoch 批次大小为 32
We load the model weights that got the best validation accuracy and we
加载验证准确率最高的模型权重
see that our CNN gets a test accuracy of about 66%.
我们的 CNN 测试准确率大概为 66%
This is an excellent improvement over the MLP we just trained.
相对于刚刚训练的 MLP 而言 改善了很多
Of course, there's plenty of room to tinker with and optimize the CNN further.
当然 该 CNN 还有很多改进的余地
We encourage you to do this.
建议你继续改进它
It's a great learning experience.
这将是个很好的学习经历
We should mention that in 2015,
顺便提下 在 2015 年
there was an online competition where data scientists
网上出现了一项竞赛
competed to classify images in the CIFAR-10 database.
数据科学家针对 CIFAR-10 数据集图片分类任务展开竞争
The winning architecture was a CNN and achieved over 95% test accuracy.
获胜的架构是 CNN 测试准确率超过了 95%
It took 90 hours to train on a GPU.
在 GPU 上的训练时间为 90 小时
If you'd like to read about this architecture,
如果你想了解这一架构
please check out the link below.
请参阅下方的链接